Right now, this serial killer could be looking at his next victim.
The Bone Collector is a crime, thriller, drama film directed by Phillip Noyce.
Lincoln Rhyme was the department's top homicide detective and leading expert in criminal
forensics until an injury left him paralyzed, depressed, and incapable of working.
But when a gruesome murder in Manhattan leaves detectives
baffled, they call on Rhyme to help solve the mystery.
Amelia Donaghy, a rookie cop whose quick thinking preserved a gruesome murder
scene, is enlisted by Rhyme to be his on-the-scene forensics expert.
With Amelia reluctantly acting as Rhyme's able-bodied go-between, the pair piece together cryptic clues the
killer leaves behind at the scene of the crime, hoping to catch the grisly serial killer.
Lincoln Rhyme, played by Denzel Washington.
Amelia Donaghy, played by Angelina Jolie.
Thelma, played by Queen Latifah.
Captain Howard Cheney, played by Michael Rooker.
Detective Kenny Solomon, played by Michael McGlone.
Eddie Ortiz, played by Luis Guzmán.
The Bone Collector is a 1999 American psychological crime thriller film directed by
Phillip Noyce and starring Denzel Washington and Angelina Jolie.
An adaptation of the 1997 crime novel of the same name by Jeffery Deaver, it focuses on a quadriplegic homicide detective (Washington)
and a newly-recruited patrol officer (Jolie) investigating the esoteric crimes of a serial killer in New York City.
The film explores themes of new york city, taxi, based on
novel or book, psychopath, taxi driver.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.